嘿伙计们，我们今天在避难所
hey folks we're out on the refuge today
玩一些花哨的新技术
playing around with some fancy new technology
我们将其中三个定位在跟踪凸轮
trail cams we're positioning three of these at
避难所周围的不同区域
different areas around the refuge
然后留意事情
then to keep an eye on things
我们可以从每个
we can get a snapshot image from each
通过发送请求相机
camera by sending a request
到一个 api
to an api
我们回到工作室
we're back in the studio
你可以看到我们添加了一个摄像头
and you can see that we've added a video cam
ex 文件在这里，像往常一样你会发现
ex file here and as usual you'll find
代码包中的这个和其他准备好的文件
this and other prepared files in the code bundle
在这个文件中只是为了找到一个名为 video cam 的模块
in this file just to find a module called video cam
模拟向外部 api 发送请求
that simulates sending a request to an external api
然后我们可以从摄像机中获取快照图像
then we can get a snapshot image from a video camera
所以调用的函数得到了小睡
so the functions called gets napshot
我们给它一个相机名称
we give it a camera name
和
and
在这里，您将放置实际代码以发送请求
here you would put the actual code to send a request
到那个外部 api
to that external api
但我们不会为此担心
but we're not going to worry about that
我们只是要模拟
we're just going to simulate
它可能相对较慢
that it can be relatively slow
通过睡一秒钟
by sleeping for one second
然后它会返回一些响应
and then it's going to return some response
所以我们有一个示例响应
and so we've got an example response
那将被退回
that would be returned
从那个api
from that api
我们只取相机名称
we just take the camera name
添加连字符 dashnapshot
add a hyphen dashnapshot
JPEG
jpeg
现在我们只是返回这个小睡的文件名
now we're just returning the file name of this napshot
但你可以想象它会返回一个完整的
but you can imagine that it would return a full
指向位于某处图像服务器上的文件的 URL
url to a file living on an image server somewhere
所以如果我们调用那个函数
so if we call that function
我就传一个摄像头
I'll just pass in cam one
好吧，需要一秒钟才能得到回应
well it takes a second to get a response
它只返回该文件名
and it just returns that file name
凸轮二相同
same for cam two
我们只是在一秒钟后得到一个不同的文件名
we just get a different file name after a second
和凸轮三
and cam three
在处理程序 dx 中，我们已经有一个
and in handler dx we already have a
为我们获取三个快照的快照路线
snapshot's route that gets us three snapshots
是的，它调用了该函数三遍
yeah it calls that function three times
所以我们得到三个
so we get back three
不同的文件名
different file names
然后我们将这些文件名放入快照列表
we then put those file names into a snapshots list
然后我们检查那个列表
and then we inspect that list
这构成了我们的响应主体
and that makes up our response body
我们不会担心图像会如何得到
we won't worry about how the images would get
呈现在页面上
rendered on a page
只是这样我们就可以留在话题上
just so we can stay on topic
你会注意到我们可以这样称呼
and you'll notice we could call that
获取快照功能
get snapshot function
来自摄像头模块
from the video cam module
那是因为我们有别名
and that's because we have that aliased in
在上面
up here at the top
别名调查摄像机
alias survey videocam
现在让我们自己生成服务器
now let's spawn the server in its own
处理，以便我们可以继续使用 iex
process so we can continue to use iex
我们在上一个模块中学习了如何做到这一点
and we learned how to do this in the previous module
在这种情况下，我们将使用命名函数调用 spawn
in this case we'll call spawn with the named function
所以它将成为我们的模块 hp 服务器
so it's going to be our module hp server
该功能将启动
the function is going to be start
然后我们给它一个参数列表
and then we give it a list of arguments
我们将再次在端口 4000 上启动它
we're going to start it on port 4000 again
然后在另一个终端会话中结束
then over in a different terminal session
我们可以发送请求以获取快照
we can send a request to get the snapshots
这只是一个请求
it's just going to be a request
本地那 4000 个斜线快照
to local those 4000 slash snapshots
我们必须等待请求
and we have to wait for the request
这将需要一个完整的
and it's going to take a full
3秒得到回复
3 seconds to get back the response which
在那些文件名的列表中
is at the list of those file names
所以它需要 3 秒也就不足为奇了
so it shouldn't be any surprise that it takes 3 seconds
因为路由调用获取快照功能
because the route calls to get snapshot function
三次，我们知道每个 api 请求
three times and we know that each api request
需要一秒钟
takes one second
啊，但我们知道如何更有效地做到这一点
ah but we know how to do this more efficiently with
我们看到的进程 iex 在它自己的进程中运行
processes as we saw iex runs in its own process
在 iex 中，我们生成了我们的 http 服务器
and while in iex we spawn our http server
所以服务器在自己的进程中运行
so the server is running in its own process
然后当我们向我们的服务器发送请求时
then when we send a request to our server
更安全的熊
safer bears
它产生另一个进程来处理该请求
it spawns another process to handle that request
并且一旦将响应发送回客户端
and once it is send a response back to the client
该进程退出
that process exits
以同样的方式
in the same way
我们对快照的新请求又产生了另一个
our new requests for snapshot spawns yet another
处理该请求的过程
process to handle that request
现在在那个过程中，我们发送了三个
right now in that process we send three
api 请求顺序
api requests sequentially
因为每个请求都需要一秒钟
and since each request takes one second
该过程必须等待整整 3 秒
the process has to wait a full 3 seconds
在发回响应之前
before sending back a response
相反，我们可以生成每个 api 请求
instead we can spawn each api request
在自己的进程中，因此它们并行运行
in its own process so they run in parallel
所以进程可以产生其他进程
so processes can spawn other processes
这样请求处理过程将
and that way the request handling process will
只需要最慢的 api 请求
only take as long as the slowest api request
在我们的例子中只是一秒钟
which in our case is just one second
在我们的路线功能中
in our route function
我们知道如何在自己的进程中生成 api 请求
we know how to spawn an api request in its own process
所以这是我们将调用的函数 spawn
so here's the function we'll just call spawn
给它匿名函数
give it anonymous function there
运行那个
run that
在匿名函数中获取快照函数
get snapshot function inside of the anonymous function
如果会发生什么
and what's going to happen if
我们这样做
we do this
好吧，让我们把它复制出来，然后在 iux 中尝试一下
well let's copy it out and just try it in iux
所以我会把它粘贴进去
so I'll paste it in
我需要更改它以使用
I need to change this to use
服务点，因为我们这里没有别名
servy dot because we don't have the alias here
它返回
it return
它创建了一个进程，它将运行
and it creates a process and it's going to run
在该过程中获取快照功能
that get snapshot function in that process
但我们只是在这里看到 pid
but we just see the pid right here
这就是 spawn 函数返回的内容
that's what's returned by the spawn function
但我们没有看到返回的值
but we don't see the value that's returned by
获取快照功能
the get snapshot function
这将是文件名
that's going to be the file name
我们只得到 pid
we just get the pid
因为这是 spawn 函数返回的
because that's what's returned by the spawn function
所以现在回到我们的处理程序文件
so now back over in our handler file
这真的不是快照之一
this really isn't snapshot one
这是一个 pid，所以我们称它为 pid one
this is a pid so let's call it pid one
但是现在我们遇到了一个问题
but now we've got a problem right
我们有一个 pid，但我们真正需要的是快照
we've got a pid but what we really need is snapshots
我们需要创建一个快照或文件名列表
we need to create a list of snapshots or file names
所以我们需要一些方法来返回
so we need some way to return
此返回的文件名
the file name that's returned by this
获取快照功能
get snapshot function
到产生它的过程
to the process that spawned it
在这种情况下
in this case
该进程是运行此进程的进程
that process is the one that's running this
路由功能
route function
所以我们有两个过程，因为
so we have two processes and since
一个进程产生另一个进程
one process spawned the other
您可以将此过程视为父进程
you can think of this process as the parent
而这个过程就是孩子
and this process is the child
此过程从外部 api 获取文件名
this process gets a file name from an external api
然后需要将该文件名发送到该进程
and then needs to send that file name to this process
但它怎么能做到这一点
but how can it do that
如果进程同时运行并且
if the processes run concurrently and
不要分享任何东西
don't share anything
好吧，您可以将流程视为有点像
well you can think of processes as being kind of like
我们都在同时做事的人
people we're all doing things concurrently
而且我们经常需要异步通信
and we often need to communicate asynchronously
让每个人继续
allowing each person to carry on
不受他们正在做的任何事情的干扰
uninterrupted with whatever they're doing
我们怎么做
how do we do that
当我们互相发送
while we send each other
同步消息，例如电子邮件和文本
a synchronous messages such as emails and text
最终出现在某种邮箱中
which end up in some kind of mailbox
同样每个进程都有一个邮箱
likewise each process has a mailbox
它是在创建进程时创建的
it's created when the process is created
在我们的例子中，我们是
in our case we're
只关心发送给
only concerned with messages sent to the
父进程
parent process
所以我们将专注于它的邮箱
so we'll focus on its mailbox
每个邮箱都有一个地址
each mailbox has an address
这是进程的pid
it's the pid of the process
发送异步消息
to send an asynchronous message
到进程的邮箱
to the process's mailbox
我们用两个参数调用 send
we call send with two arguments
发送消息的进程的坑
the pit of the process to send the message to
本例中的父 pid 和要发送的消息
the parent pid in this case and the message to send
消息可以是任何长生不老药
messages can be any elixir term
例如我们可以只发送文件名
for example we could just send the file name
但通常使用元组
but it's common to use a tuple
用一些标识符标记消息
to tag the message with some identifier
我们任意选择将其标记为结果的原子
an atom we've arbitrarily chosen to tag it as result
但它可以是任何东西
but it could be anything
发送消息
sending a message puts that
进程邮箱中的消息
message in the process's mailbox
与您决定何时检查邮箱的方式不同
not unlike how you decide when to check your mailbox
一个过程得到决定
a process gets decide
当它想阅读它的消息时
when it wants to read its messages
当它准备好时，它用一个块调用接收
when it's ready it calls receive with a block
在块内我们使用模式来匹配消息
inside the block we use patterns to match messages
当消息与此模式匹配时
when a message matches this pattern
在这种情况下，该过程对其起作用
the process acts upon it in this case
我们只是想提取文件名并返回它
we simply want to extract the file name and return it
并且因为接收
and because the receive
函数返回最后一个值
function returns the value of the last
匹配爪中的表达
expression in the matching claws
我们可以将它绑定到一个变量
we can bind it to a variable
已匹配此消息
having matched this message
它已从邮箱中删除
it's removed from the mailbox
现在我们真正想做的是生成三个
now what we really want to do is spawn three
一次处理所有进程，因此它们并行运行
processes all at once so they run in parallel
每个流程都会发送最终的
each process will send the final
从外部 api 获得的名称
name it got from the external api
回到同一个父进程
back to the same parent process
当父母准备好时
when the parent is ready
它会一一读取消息
it reads the messages one by one
通过调用接收三次
by calling receive three times
每条消息一次
once for each message
这样父进程就可以收集
in this way the parent process can collect
列表中的所有文件名
all the file names in a list
你会经常听到这个
you'll often hear this
称为并发的actor模型
referred to as the actor model of concurrency
每个过程都是一个行动者，生活在自己独立的环境中
each process is an actor living in its own independent
孤立的小世界
isolated little world
它不与其他进程共享任何内容
it doesn't share anything with other processes
进程可以通信的唯一方式
the only way processes can communicate
是通过发送和接收消息
is by sending and receiving messages
让我们在 iex 中试一试
let's give this a whirl in iex
我们想产生一个进程并让它发送一个结果
we want to spawn a process and have it send a result
回到父进程
back to the parent process
那么谁是父进程
so who's the parent process
好
well
我们将从这个 iex 会话中生成
we're going to do the spawning from this iex session
所以这是你记得的父进程
so it's the parent process you remember
可以通过调用获取当前进程的坑
you can get the pit of the current process by calling
self 所以 iex 会话进程被绑定到 48
self so the iex session process is pied to 48
我要签那个
and I'm going to sign that
pid 到对父级的变量调用
pid to a variable call to parent
我马上解释为什么
and I'll explain why in a minute now
我们可以生成一个进程并使用该 pid
we can spawn a process and use that pid
将消息发送回 iex 进程
to send a message back to the iex process
为此，我们使用发送功能
and to do that we use the send function
我们想把它发回给父母
we want to send it back to the parent
所以我们给它父母的pid
so we give it the parents pid
然后我们给它信息
and then we give it the message
在这种情况下，我们的信息将是一个错误
in this case our message is going to be a toople
但正如煤炭所说，您可以使用任何长生不老药
but as the coal said you can use any elixir term
所以我们要使用一个工具
so we're going to use a toople
我们将用结果标记它
we're going to tag it with result
同样，这只是任意的，您可以在那里使用任何标签
again that's just arbitrary you could use any tag there
然后我们要输入我们的实际文件名
and then we want to put in our actual file name
所以我将使用一张快照 jpeg
so I'm going to use one snapshot jpeg
in spawn 立即返回并给我们 pid
in spawn returns immediately and gives us the pid
所以spawn进程是pid 2 78
so the spawn process is pid two seventy eight
但这就是我们得到的所有输出
but that's all the output that we get
但我们知道调用 sind
but we know that calling sind
将把这条消息
is going to put this message
在这个pid的父邮箱中
in the mailbox of the parent which is this pid
所以让我们在那个邮箱里来个高峰吧
so let's just take a peaky peak at that mailbox
我们可以通过调用流程模块来做到这一点
and we can do that by calling the process modules
信息功能
info function
这只是让我们查询
and this just lets us query
进程的不同属性
different attributes of a process
所以我们要看看父进程
so we want to look at the parent process
我们想看看你的邮箱里有什么消息
and we want to see what messages are in your mailbox
我们看到有一条信息就在这里
and we see that there's one message it's right here
现在您注意到它已转换为关键字列表
now you notice it converted into a keyword list
我们像这样使用了两极
we used a two pole right like that
但它只是将其显示为关键字列表
but it just displayed it as a keyword list
无论如何，邮箱只有一条消息
in any event the mailbox has one message
现在，当您以这种方式使用流程信息时
now when you use process info this way
它只是向我们展示了邮箱中的内容
it just shows us what's in the mailbox
它实际上并没有删除任何消息
it doesn't actually take out any of the messages
此时生成过程早已不复存在
at this point the spawn process is long gone
它唯一的工作就是向父母发送一条消息
its only job was to send a message back to the parent
然后它退出了
then it exited
我们可以让消息坐在邮箱中
and we can let the message sit in the mailbox
直到我们准备好做某事
until we're ready to do something
有了它，邮件将保留在邮箱中
with it messages will remain in the mailbox
直到他们被明确收到
until they're explicitly received
或在这种情况下父进程终止
or the process the parent in this case terminates
现在假设我们已经准备好接收消息
now let's say we're ready to receive the message
为此，我们调用接收并给它一个块
and to do that we call receive and we give it a block
我将在 iux 中有多行
and I'm just going to have multiple lines here in iux
我只是要返回
I'm just going to hit return
然后在那个街区里面
and then inside of that block
我们需要一个模式
we need a pattern that
匹配邮箱中的邮件
matches the message in the mailbox
所以它是一个元组
so it's a tuple
有原子结果
has the atom result
然后它有一个文件名，我们要绑定它
then it has a file name and we want to bind that
到一个变量
to a variable
我将其命名为文件名
I'm going to call it file name
当消息与该模式匹配时
and when the message matches that pattern
我们要返回提取的文件名
we want to return the extracted file name
所以我们就这样做
so we just do that
然后我们就在街区里
and then we'll just in the block
我们看到结果是一张快照 jpeg
and we see the result is one snapshot jpeg
所以当我们打电话时收到它
so when we call receive it
检查邮箱中的邮件
examine the message in the mailbox
它匹配这个模式
it match this pattern
所以这成为这里接收函数的结果
so this becomes the result of the receive function here
这就是为什么我们在 ix 中看到一个快照 jpeg 的值
and that's why we see the value one snapshot jpeg in ix
一旦我们收到消息
once we've received the message
它已从邮箱中删除
it's removed from the mailbox
所以如果我们再试一次
so if we try this again
邮箱应该是空的，果然是
the mailbox should be empty and sure enough it is
让我们在另一条消息中使用不同的文件名
let's in another message with a different file name
我将把它称为两个快照
I'm going to call it two snapshot
然后我将在一条线上收到它
and then I'm going to receive it on one line
所以模式是结果
so the pattern is result
捕获文件名
capture the file name
返回文件名结束
return the file name end
并将该消息与快照匹配
and it match that message to snapshot
现在邮箱又是空的
and now the mailbox is empty again
那么如果我们调用receive会发生什么
so what would happen if we call receive
在邮件实际到达邮箱之前
before a message actually arrives in the mailbox
很好地设置它
well to set that up
我们将让这个绑定进程休眠 15 秒
we'll have this bond process sleep for 15 seconds
在发送结果之前
before sending the result
所以我将其更改为三个快照只是为了使它
so I'll change this to three snapshot just to make it
不同的
different
然后在我们犯罪之前，我将使用计时器
and then before we do the sin I'm going to use timer
睡眠 15 秒
sleep 15 seconds
把我们放进我的结肠
and just put us in my colon
所以我们有两个表达式
so we have two expressions there
我们要睡觉了
we're going to sleep
然后我们要发送
and then we're going to do the send
现在让我们立即查看邮箱
now let's immediately peek in the mailbox
好吧，它仍然是空的，现在让我们调用接收
well it's still empty and now let's call receive
看起来它只是挂在那里
well it looks like it's just hanging there
它挂了，因为接收是一个阻塞调用
and it's hanging because receive is a blocking call
它正在等待邮件到达邮箱
it's waiting for a message to arrive in the mailbox
如果你打电话接收
if you call receive
并且邮箱不包含任何匹配的消息
and the mailbox doesn't contain any matching messages
那么在这种情况下是 ix 的当前进程
then the current process which is ix in this case
挂起直到匹配的消息到达
suspends until a matching message arrives
然后终于在 15 秒后我们收到了消息
and then finally after 15 seconds we get the message
接收虽然很耐心
receive is patient though
它会无限期地等待
it would have waited indefinitely
现在如果我们产生三个进程，每个进程会发生什么
now what happens if we spawn three processes that each
向家长邮箱发送消息
send a message to the parent's mailbox
首先我们将发送快照二
first we'll send snapshot two
然后我们将发送快照一
then we'll send snapshot one
然后我们将发送快照三
then we'll send snapshot three
然后我们去邮箱看看
and then we'll have a look in the mailbox
好吧，现在我们在邮箱中有一个消息列表
well now we have a list of messages in the mailbox
并且它们的订购方式相同
and they're ordered in the same
我们发送它们的顺序
order in which we sent them
我们先发送了两个快照
we sent snapshot two first
然后快照一然后快照三
then snapshot one then snapshot three
所以这给了我们一个快照两个
so that gives us a snapshot two
它已从他们的邮箱中删除
and it's removed from their mailbox
快照一，然后快照三
snapshot one and then snapshot three
现在注意消息是在相同的
now notice the messages are received in the same
命令他们到达邮箱
order they arrived in the mailbox
换句话说，它是先进先出
in other words it's first in first out
或先收到
or first in first received
邮箱里又是空的
in the mailboxes once again empty
好的，所以当我们开始时
okay so when we started
为什么我们将父母 pid 分配给变量
why did we assign the parents pid to a variable
然后我们向那个家长发送了一条消息
and then we sent a message to that parent
那么为什么我们可以在这里使用 self
so why can we have just use self right here
我们看到它产生了一个进程
we see that it spawns a process
所以如果父母和自我是同一件事
so if parent and self are the same thing
那么消息应该在父母的邮箱中
then the message should be in the parent's mailbox
嗯，但家长的邮箱是空的
hmm but the parent's mailbox is empty
事实证明这是一个非常常见的错误
well it turns out this is a really common mistake
请记住
remember that
self 返回当前进程的pid
self returns the pid of the current process
所以当我们在这里调用 self 时
so when we call self up here
当前进程就是这个iexcession进程
the current process is this iexcession process
它返回该进程的 pid
and it returns the pid of that process
但在里面叫自己
but calling self inside of
这个 spawn 函数就在这里
this spawn function right here
将返回 pid
is going to return the pid
那个产卵过程
of that spawn process
所以父母和自己不是一回事
so parent and self aren't the same thing
当这个生成过程运行时
when this spawn process runs
重要的是要记住 pid 返回
it's important to keep in mind that the pid return by
自我改变取决于它被调用的地方
self changes depending on where it's called
当它在这里被调用时
when it's called here
这将是 iexcession 过程
it's going to be the iexcession process
当它在这里被调用时
when it's called here
这将是正在产生的过程
it's going to be the process that's being spawned
这就是为什么我们必须保存自我的价值
that's why we had to save the value of self
在产生进程之前
before spawning the process
因为自我会改变
because self's going to change
但是父母不会改变，因为我们已经把它保存了
but parent won't change because we've saved it off
如果我们发送给自己
if we send to self
然后将消息放入 spawn 的邮箱
then the message is put in the mailbox of the spawn
处理但随后该邮箱被破坏
process but then that mailbox gets destroyed
当生成进程退出时
when the spawn process exits
所以除非你真的想发消息
so unless you really want to send a message
回到你自己
back to yourself
你通常不会打电话
you typically won't call
在 spawn 函数中的 self
self inside of a spawn function
发送消息
to send a message
相反，您将拥有一个类似于父级的变量
instead you'll have a variable something like a parent
你要把消息发回给
that you're going to send the message back to
现在我们知道如何解决我们最初的问题
now we know how to solve our original problem
是的，当我们产生这个过程时
yeah when we spawn this process
我们需要发送消息
we need to send a message
回到父进程
back to the parent process
这是过程
which is the process
首先调用这个路由函数
that called this route function in the first place
并且该消息将包括以下结果
and that message is going to include the result of
调用获取快照
calling get snapshot
现在让我们只关注第一个 api 请求
now let's just focus on the first api request
所以我们实际上可以注释掉另外两个相机
so we can actually comment out these other two cameras
我们想发回消息给
and we want to send a message back to
父进程所以我们需要做的第一件事
the parent process so the first thing we need to do
是保存那个父进程
is save off that parent process
我们将保存父母等于自我
we'll save the parent equals self
在这种情况下，这是
and in this context this is the
请求处理流程
request handling process
这就是我们在 http 服务器中产生的过程
that's the process we spawn in http server
运行路由功能
that runs the route function
现在你可能会看到这被称为调用者
now you might see this referred to as the caller
因为它是pid
since it's the pid
调用此函数的进程
of the process that called this function
但为了保持一致，我们将保留名称 parent
but to stay consistent we'll keep the name parent
那么当我们产生这个过程时
then when we spawn this process
我们想发回一条消息
we want to send a message back to that
所以我们会发送
so we will send
给父母
to the parent
调用此函数的结果
the result of calling this function
但我们要把它包装成元组
but we're going to wrap it into tuple
所以这将是结果
so it's going to be result
然后是第二个
and then the second
该元组中的元素将是
element in that tuple is going to be
调用的结果被打盹
the result of calling gets napshot
我们不需要这个 pid
and we don't need this pid
所以我要在前面摆脱这个
so I'm just going to get rid of this on the front
然后一旦我们产生那个过程
then once we spawn that process
我们会立即致电接收
we'll immediately call receive
并等待消息到达
and wait for the message to arrive
所以我们会说快照一
so we'll say snapshot one
等于接收
equals receive
我们将放入该模式
we'll put in that pattern
返回提取的文件名
return the extracted file name
就像我们以前一样
just like we did before
现在重要的是要注意这个接收
now it's important to note that this receive
在父进程中被调用
is getting called in the parent process
因为在父母中我们要等待
because in the parent we want to wait
消息到达
for the message to arrive
从那个产生的过程
from that spawned process
因为我们只期待一种信息
and because we only expect one kind of message
我们只需要对该消息进行模式匹配
we just need to pattern match on that message
现在进程可以发送和接收多个
now processes can send and receive multiple
不同类型的消息
different kinds of messages
像这样
as such
接收可以匹配多个模式的消息
receive can match messages against multiple patterns
类似于 case 表达式的工作方式
similar to how a case expression works
有多个从句
with multiple clauses
我们实际上会看到一个例子
we'll actually see an example of that
在后面的部分
in the later section
现在虽然我们只需要一种模式
for now though we just need one pattern
然后一旦我们得到最后的快照
then once we get that final even snapshot one
我们只需要记住返回
we just need to remember to return
快照一张在这里
snapshot one here
因为我们还没有快照列表
because we don't yet have a list of snapshots
我们只有一个
we just have one
所以如果我们把它保存起来
so if we save that away
现在我们需要重新启动我们的服务器
now we're going to need to restart our server
所以我只是要重新启动ix
so I'm just going to restart ix
然后我们将生成我们的服务器
then we'll spawn our server
然后我们将发送快照请求
then we'll send a request for snapshots
它应该返回一个文件名
and it should return a file name
确实如此
and indeed it does
这很酷
and that's pretty cool
这是一个很好的开始
this is a great start
现在我们只需要做同样的事情
now we just need to do the same
其他两个相机的东西
thing for the other two cameras
所以让我们继续复制代码
so let's go ahead and duplicate the code
因为它展示了一些有趣的东西
because it demonstrates something interesting
现在别担心，我们稍后会清理它
now don't worry we'll clean this up later
我只是要复制这两行
I'm just going to copy these two lines
我们将在这里删除此评论
we'll get rid of this comment here
我只是要粘贴我复制的内容
I'm just going to paste in what I copied
所以这将用于凸轮二
so this is going to be for cam two
然后我们会得到快照二
and then we'll get snapshot two
我再贴一次
I'll paste it again
这将用于凸轮三
this is going to be for cam three
我们会得到快照三
and we'll get snapshot three
然后我们可以取消注释这个列表
then we can uncomment this list
所以我们把快照放在一张
so we put snapshot one
列表中的两个和三个
two and three in a list
然后我们只需要返回
and then we just need to return
该列表，所以我们将调用检查
that list so we'll call inspect on
现在的快照
snapshots now
所以把它保存起来
so save that away
我们将再次重新启动我们的服务器
we'll restart our server again
以及可能出什么问题
and what could go wrong
让我们继续发送请求
let's go ahead and send the request
哇，还需要3秒
whoa it still takes 3 seconds
为什么那么好，因为记住接收块
why well because remember that receive blocks
对，我们发送一个请求
right we send one request
然后等待调用receive的结果
and then wait for the result calling receive
在发送下一个请求之前
before sending the next request
所以即使每个
so even though each
进程同时运行
process runs concurrently
我们的代码被有效地序列化了
our code is effectively serialized
现在这是相当明显的，因为重复
now this is fairly obvious because of the duplication
但它是一个警告，要注意阻止
but it serves as a warning to be mindful of blocking
成为代码中同步点的调用
calls that become synchronization points in your code
并且接收是那些阻塞呼叫之一
and receive is one of those blocking calls
解决这个问题
to fix this problem
我们需要做的就是重新排列代码
all we need to do is rearrange the code
所以我们首先产生这个过程
so that we spawn the process as first
然后接收所有消息
then receive all the messages
所以我会把这个债券搬到这里
so I'll take this bond and move it up here
与此债券相同
same with this bond
然后我们将在那之后做所有的接收
and then we'll do all the receives after that
所以现在
so now
所有进程都将立即生成
all the processes are going to get spawned at once
这将很快发生
this is going to happen really fast
然后我们等待三个消息
and then we wait for the three messages
最快的api请求
the fastest api request
会先发消息
is going to send a message first
所以它将是邮箱中的第一个
so it's going to be the first one in the mailbox
然后是下一个最快的
and then the next fastest
最后是最慢的
and then finally the slowest one
但总的来说
but overall
因为进程同时运行
since the processes are running concurrently
我们只需要等多久
we only have to wait as long
作为最慢的 api 请求
as the slowest api request
在我们的例子中只是一秒钟
which in our case is just one second
所以现在如果我们把它保存起来
so now if we save this away
再次重启服务器
restart the server again
现在让我们最后一次尝试这个请求
and now let's try that request one final time
我们在一秒钟内获得所有三个快照
and we get all three snapshots in just one second
每个进程并行运行
each of the processes are running in parallel
这真的很甜
which is really sweet
协调同步工作
to coordinate a synchronous work
我们所要做的就是产卵
all we had to do was spawn
沙并接收
sand and receive
现在值得承认的是
now it's worth recognizing that this
仅适用于单个 api 请求
only works because the individual api requests
不要互相依赖
don't depend on each other
当你有这样的独立工作块时
and when you have independent chunks of work like this
你可以并行运行
that you can run in parallel
将购买一切手段
will buy all means
充分利用权力
take full advantage of the power
Elixir 的并发模型
of elixir's concurrency model
在下一节
in the next section
我们将删除我们在此处看到的重复项
we'll remove the duplication we see here
并发现运行的抽象
and discover an abstraction for running
任何异步任务
any task asynchronously